Osodo Rodney David

 $rodnevosodo.com \mid me@rodnevosodo.com \mid linkedin.com/in/rodnevosodo \mid github.com/0x6f736f646f$

I am a technology enthusiast, with a burning interest in the electronics industry. I have a newfound love for sustainable energy triggered by my intuition to make our future better. I am currently pursuing my dream in Mechatronics Engineering with the hope of becoming a better doctoral researcher particularly in Kenya where the field is currently not robust. I am currently working on the design and fabrication of a prototype mobile platform with holonomic and omnidirectional motion and have previously developed the ujuzi device to monitor your energy consumption.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Assembly, Rust, Python, C/C++, SQL (Postgres), Matlab, HTML/CSS

Design Tools: Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk CFD, Proteus, EasyEDA, KiCAD, Atmel Studio Developer Tools: Git, Docker, Travis-CI, Google Cloud Platform, Visual Studio, PyCharm, CLion

Technologies: CNC Machining, Milling, Welding, 3D printing, PCB Etching, Embedded Systems, Artificial Intelligence

EDUCATION

IBM Summer School

Online

Quantum Computing, Minor in Machine Learning

Sep. 2020 and Sep 2021

Nairobi, KE

Bachelor of Science in Mechatronics Engineering

Sep. 2017 - Dec 2022

- Designed wearable device that helps the visually challenged people to accomplish their day to day task
- Designing and fabricating a prototype mobile platform with holonomic and omnidirectional motion

Experience

Software Engineer

July 2019 - Present

Juja, Nairobi Qualislabs, KE

- I worked with hardware and firmware engineers to build our API responsible for image processing.
- I was able to set up a Kubernetes cluster to handle all our API calls.

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

• Implemented our three models, Image captioning, Optical character recognition and Emotion detection.

Rocket Scientist Intern

February 2021 - May 2021

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Nakuja Project, KE

- I was able to do a comprehensive design of the rocket sub-system, Avionics and Airframe.
- Implemented Kalman filter using sensor fusion to detect apogee.
- I was able to participate in the SRI conference and submitted a technical paper

Mechanical Engineer Intern

September 2019 – October 2019

Rift Valley Machineries Service, Nairobi

Industrial Area, KE

• I was able to learn Generator installations, servicing and maintaining generators, pump installations, posho mill assembly, farm machinery assembly and assembly and operation of construction machinery

Projects

Design and fabrication of a holonomic and omnidirectional mobile platform

May 2022 – Present

- Mechanical chassis and platform design
- Independent control of motor rotational and translational motion

Design of a Manual Shearing Machine | Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk FEA

June 2021 – August 2021

• Carried out a Finite element analysis to determine maximum load

 $\textbf{Fabricated a Spool valve} \mid \textit{Autodesk Inventor, Lathe Machine}$

January 2019 - March 2019

• Machined the spool valve using facing, turning, parting, threading and drilling

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- Submitted a paper to the SRI conference held at JKUAT
- Won the JKUAT Tech Expo 10.0
- Regional Finalist at the IBM Call for Code Challenge